phoenixpubliclibrary.org 2012-05-27

# Phoenix Public Library - www.phoenixpubliclibrary.org

Phoenix Public Library safeguards personally identifiable information. Such information is only disclosed when required by law or for collection of outstanding fees. Phoenix Public Library collects and uses customers' personal information to operate Library websites and deliver requested services. The following guidelines provide information about the types of information collected, how the information is used and when it is disclosed.

 **Guidelines**

 _Collection of Personal Information_

  1. Statistical Information: Phoenix Public Library collects information to maintain the quality of its services and to report aggregate information on the usage of its website to City management, as well as state and federal agencies and national library organizations. Such information can include IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and referring website addresses. 
  2. Personally-identifiable Information: Phoenix Public Library may collect personally-identifiable information, such as customer e-mail addresses, names, home or work addresses or telephone numbers. Information collected through one of Phoenix Public Library's websites may be utilized by the Library to provide services through any of its websites. 
  3. The Library assumes no responsibility if a customer directly discloses personally-identifiable information or personally-sensitive data through other websites, chat rooms, online communities or other public online forums, resulting in this information being collected and used by others.

 _Use of Personal Information_

Phoenix Public Library websites collect and use customer personal information to operate Phoenix Public Library websites and deliver requested services. Phoenix Public Library does not sell, rent, lease or otherwise provide its customer lists or customer-controlled information to third parties.

As a matter of business practice, when customer overdue fees reach a total of $75 or more, customers account information is forwarded electronically to a collection agency.

Customer information may be subject to disclosure under Arizona Public Records Law except to the extent it is privileged or confidential.

 _Control of Personal Information_

Certain Library services require the use of a library card number and customer or user name in order to access the service. At any time while accessing any of the Phoenix Public Library's websites, customers may decline participation in any activity that requests information (such as surveys or emails).

 _Collection of Information on Use of Library Computers (PCs)_

The information collected on usage of public computers at Phoenix Public Library falls into two categories:

  1. Reservations: The Library's PC Reservation System retains information on the customer's library card barcode, computer reserved and the date and time of every public computer session for up to 60 days.
  2. Internet Usage: The Library preserves information on all Internet activity on its public-use computers, including uploading and downloading, for a minimum of 30 days.
  3. Records are accessible to law enforcement agencies with a court order.

 _Use of Cookies_

A "cookie" is information that a website puts on a computer's hard drive so that it can remember something about the user later. Most commonly, a cookie records an individual's preferences in using a certain website.

  1. Persistent Cookies: Phoenix Public Library does not use persistent cookies to collect permanent information.
  2. Non-Persistent Cookies: Phoenix Public Library may use non-persistent cookies in applications that keep track of a customer's session. Non-persistent cookies are only necessary to maintain session information. Non-persistent cookies are temporary and are invalidated once a customer's session is completed.
  3. Public-accessed computers at Phoenix Public Library do not have the ability to decline cookies. To fully experience the interactive features of the Internet, publicly-accessible computers allow the placement of both persistent and non-persistent cookies. As the use of cookies on publicly-accessible computers is outside the control of Phoenix Public Library, personally-identifiable information associated with these cookies may be used by others.

 **Approved by Library Advisory Board June 16, 2010.**
